import { Question, ReadingQuestion } from "./types";

export const data: (Question | ReadingQuestion)[] = [
    {
      "id": 0,
      "question": "The population of City X increased from 2 million in the year 2000 to 2.5 million in 2015 and the gross domestic product of the city in 2000 was 38% less than that in 2015. What was the approximate percent change, rounded to the nearest integer if required, in the per capita gross domestic product of the city from 2000 to 2015?",
      "answers": [
        "22% decrease",
        "22% increase",
        "28% increase",
        "53% increase",
        "113% increase"
      ],
      "type": "Quantitative Reasoning - Problem Solving",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "A box contains 20 balls, of which 12 are red and 8 are blue. If two balls are to be drawn from this box at random without replacement, what is the probability that one ball will be red and the other will be blue?",
      "answers": [
        "1/96",
        "6/25",
        "24/95",
        "48/95",
        "1"
      ],
      "type": "Quantitative Reasoning - Problem Solving",
      "correct": 3,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Given that:\n\n4m+n=20;\n\nand\n\n|n|≤20\n\nHow many ordered pairs (m,n) exist in which m and n both are integers?",
      "answers": [
        "Five",
        "Six",
        "Ten",
        "Eleven",
        "Forty-one"
      ],
      "type": "Quantitative Reasoning - Problem Solving",
      "correct": 3,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "In a certain class, a teacher distributed a few candies and a few bars among the students such that each student got an equal number of candies and an equal number of bars and no candies or bars remained undistributed. How many students were there in the class?\n\n(1) The teacher distributed 180 candies and 40 bars.\n(2) The total number of items received by each student was less than 20.",
      "answers": [
        "Statement (1) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (2) ALONE is not sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "Statement (2) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (1) ALONE is not sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "BOTH statements (1) and (2) TOGETHER are sufficient to answer the question asked, but NEITHER statement ALONE is sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "EACH statement ALONE is sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "Statements (1) and (2) TOGETHER are NOT sufficient to answer the question asked, and additional data specific to the problem are needed."
      ],
      "type": "Quantitative Reasoning - Data Sufficiency",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "If no bulk purchase discount applies, what is the price of 13 oranges and 12 apples?\n\n(1) The price of 39 oranges and 36 apples is $111.\n(2) The price of 3 oranges and 2 apples is $7.",
      "answers": [
        "Statement (1) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (2) ALONE is not sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "Statement (2) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (1) ALONE is not sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "BOTH statements (1) and (2) TOGETHER are sufficient to answer the question asked, but NEITHER statement ALONE is sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "EACH statement ALONE is sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "Statements (1) and (2) TOGETHER are NOT sufficient to answer the question asked, and additional data specific to the problem are needed."
      ],
      "type": "Quantitative Reasoning - Data Sufficiency",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "What is the price of an orange?\n\n(1) The price of 3 oranges and 2 apples is $7.\n(2) The price of an orange and the price of an apple are both integers.",
      "answers": [
        "Statement (1) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (2) ALONE is not sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "Statement (2) ALONE is sufficient, but statement (1) ALONE is not sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "BOTH statements (1) and (2) TOGETHER are sufficient to answer the question asked, but NEITHER statement ALONE is sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "EACH statement ALONE is sufficient to answer the question asked.",
        "Statements (1) and (2) TOGETHER are NOT sufficient to answer the question asked, and additional data specific to the problem are needed."
      ],
      "type": "Quantitative Reasoning - Data Sufficiency",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Amid the present wave of job redundancies for skilled but unemployed youth, the publication of an encouraging report on the viability of garage startup enterprises has led the Federal government to set up an investment fund, under its Federal light-industry program, to provide capital for such enterprises. This plan has drawn opposition from various quarters; the critics claim that similar funds, also set up under the Federal light-industry program, that aim to stimulate small enterprises frequently end up harming other American social groups unconnected to these enterprises.\n\nWhich of the following best provides support for the claim made by the critics above?",
      "answers": [
        "Garage enterprises in Washington State now produce almost 12% of the vehicle components previously imported from South East Asia.",
        "The funding of the Federal light-industry program depends on the reallocation of resources earmarked for disadvantaged groups.",
        "The debate concerning the Federal light-industry program created a backlog in the Federal legislative schedule.",
        "The union for Federal light-Industry workers was the prime source of the claim.",
        "Programs like Federal light-industry programs have yielded great results in past."
      ],
      "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Critical Reasoning",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Recently developed tourism infrastructure, including ten-story hotels and neon-lit discos, is obscuring the moonlight, disorienting the female turtles as they seek out beaches to lay their eggs. Often the confusion leads them to assume that the hotel pools are the sea and they end up laying their eggs in the pool flowerbeds. Once the eggs hatch, the hatchlings are unable to find their way to the sea and die. The stringent building regulations that protected the turtles in the past are being flouted openly by organized criminals who either bribe or terrorize officials into turning a blind eye.\n\nWhich of the following can be inferred from the above passage?",
      "answers": [
        "Scarcity of turtles results in ecological imbalance of sea.",
        "Chemicals in pool water are not safe for turtles.",
        "Moonlight is the only source of light for turtles.",
        "Turtles are guided by moonlight.",
        "Organized gangs are ignoring building restrictions."
      ],
      "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Critical Reasoning",
      "correct": 3,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "(1) The move to shift the fiscal obligation to provide community services away from the Federal government to the local communities is welcomed by its proponents as a step forward on the road to true democracy. They claim that by making communities responsible for funding everything from health, welfare and education to the emergency services and housing, not only will these services improve but it will also foster a greater sense of community. (2) However, such a move would mean that densely-populated areas, having a greater tax base, would be better off, and sparsely-populated, rural communities would still be dependent on supplemental subsidies from Federal sources.",
      "answers": [
        "The first is a claim that the author calls in question, and the second is a claim that goes against the first.",
        "The first is a claim that the author endorses, and the second is a claim that the author calls in question.",
        "The first is a counter-evidence to the second, and the second is the proponents' prediction.",
        "The first is the author's claim, and the second is the proponents’ finding that puts the first questionable.",
        "The first is a prediction that the author elaborates further, and the second is the objection that the argument nullifies."
      ],
      "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Critical Reasoning",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Reading Comprehension",
      "text": "To believe a proposition, say corn flakes have health benefits, is to accept it to be true. However, the question of belief is valid only for those propositions that are understandable. An understandable proposition is one that is expressed using correct grammar and known words.\n\nThe dominant view in the scientific community on how human mind believes or disbelieves an understandable proposition is the Cartesian hypothesis, propounded by the seventeenth-century philosopher René Descartes. He said that when an understandable proposition is presented to a human mind, the comprehension of its content happens automatically and passively; however, the assessment of the truth-value of that proposition is a later and deliberate act, the result of which is either belief or disbelief. Thus, this view holds that belief or disbelief in a comprehended proposition is created by rational assessment, and till such an assessment is made, the intellect neither affirms nor denies a comprehended proposition. It also suggests that the mental effort required to create belief and disbelief is the same: the effort required to assess the comprehended proposition.\n\nIn contrast, Descartes's near-contemporary Baruch Spinoza suggested that comprehension of and belief in an understandable proposition happen together, automatically and passively; he said that it is not possible to understand a proposition without, at least temporarily, accepting it to be true. On later, willful assessment, if one judges the believed proposition to be false, it may be unaccepted (disbelieved), and if judged to be true, one may continue to believe in it. Thus, as per the Spinozan hypothesis, the default setting of the human mind is to believe every understandable proposition that is presented to it; disbelief is possible but it comes – if it comes at all – from effortful, deliberate assessment done after the initial comprehension-belief.\n\nBoth hypotheses continue to have their proponents and opponents. It is, however, a common observation that doubt, suspension of judgment and disbelief are mentally taxing tasks while we naturally – effortlessly – accept and believe most of what we see, hear and read. Research has proved that we systematically err on the side of believing too much, as opposed to rejecting too much. This inherent credulity of the human mind is, in fact, the founding axiom of the fields of advertising and propaganda.\n\nAdapted from a research paper by Professor Daniel Gilbert",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "A supporter of the Cartesian hypothesis would probably agree with which of the following statements?",
          "answers": [
              "Understanding a proposition is one thing and believing another",
              "Believing is the most effortful thing that a human mind does",
              "Belief is more quickly and easily acquired than doubt",
              "Human beings are more prone to rejecting than believing propositions",
              "Human beings are skeptical and credulous in equal measure"
          ],
          "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Reading Comprehension",
          "correct": 0,
          "explanations": [],
          "difficulty": "Challenging"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "Unlike the Spinozan hypothesis, the Cartesian hypothesis suggests that at any point in time, a human mind may contain some",
          "answers": [
              "ununderstood propositions that are believed",
              "ununderstood propositions that are neither believed nor disbelieved",
              "understood propositions that are believed",
              "understood propositions that are disbelieved",
              "understood propositions that are neither believed nor disbelieved"
          ],
          "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Reading Comprehension",
          "correct": 4,
          "explanations": [],
          "difficulty": "Challenging"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "Which of the following statements about an understandable and false proposition is not supported by the Spinozan hypothesis?",
          "answers": [
            "Its comprehension is a prerequisite for its rejection.",
            "Its comprehension does not require effort.",
            "Its acceptance occurs before its rejection.",
            "Its comprehension is automatically followed by its acceptance.",
            "Its rejection does not happen automatically."
          ],
          "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Reading Comprehension",
          "correct": 3,
          "explanations": [],
          "difficulty": "Challenging"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "It can be inferred from the Spinozan hypothesis that when exposed to understandable but suspicious propositions, a person who is too distracted or tired to exert much mental effort is:",
          "answers": [
            "less likely to comprehend them than when he is alert and mentally fresh",
            "more likely to comprehend them than when he is alert and mentally fresh",
            "more likely to be uncertain and uncommitted about their truth-value than when he is alert and mentally fresh",
            "more likely to believe them than when he is alert and mentally fresh",
            "more likely to disbelieve them than when he is alert and mentally fresh"
          ],
          "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Reading Comprehension",
          "correct": 3,
          "explanations": [],
          "difficulty": "Challenging"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "It can be inferred from the passage that to make his target customers believe his advertisements, an advertiser should:",
          "answers": [
            "convey the message only using words familiar to the target customers",
            "convey the message using the traditional motifs of the target customers",
            "not use any negative words in his message",
            "not distract the customer's mind by use of images or stories",
            "not overwhelm the customer's mind by presenting a lot of information"
          ],
          "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Reading Comprehension",
          "correct": 0,
          "explanations": [],
          "difficulty": "Challenging"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "The author of the passage",
          "answers": [
            "supports the Cartesian hypothesis",
            "supports the Spinozan hypothesis",
            "has a neutral stance towards the two hypotheses",
            "rejects both the hypotheses",
            "belongs to the scientific community"
          ],
          "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Reading Comprehension",
          "correct": 1,
          "explanations": [],
          "difficulty": "Challenging"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "A magazine, as part of a survey, asked the reasons of the readers working late and the effect of their absence from home affecting their families.",
      "answers": [
        "the reasons of its readers working late and the effect of their absence from home affecting their families",
        "its readers why they worked late and their absence from home affecting their families",
        "why its readers work late and the ways in which their absence from home affects their families",
        "the reasons why its readers worked late and how their absence from home had affected their families",
        "its readers why they work late and how their absence from home affects their families"
      ],
      "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Sentence Correction",
      "correct": 4,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "But those whom willingly undertake an honest assessment of the era today are also part of an important British tradition which, though not largely forgotten, has been pushed to the limits.",
      "answers": [
        "But those whom willingly undertake an honest assessment of the era today are also part of an important British tradition which, though not largely forgotten, has been pushed to the limits.",
        "But those who are willing to undertake an honest assessment of the era today are also part of an important British tradition that, if not largely forgotten, has been pushed to the margins.",
        "But, those whom are undertaking an honest assessment of the era today willingly are also part of an important British tradition which, if not largely forgotten, has been marginalized.",
        "But those who willingly take over an honest assessment of the era today, also being part of an important British tradition which, although not largely forgotten, has been forced to the edges.",
        "But those whom are willing to undertake an honest assessment of the era today are also part of an important British tradition which, in spite of being not largely forgotten, has been pushed to the brim."
      ],
      "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Sentence Correction",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "The Brexit negotiations are faltering and the UK government's hopes to opening talks on a future trade deal with the EU this autumn looks likely to be increasingly dashed, the EU's chief negotiator, Michel Barnier, has reported back to the bloc's member states.",
      "answers": [
        "hopes to opening talks on a future trade deal with the EU this autumn looks likely to be increasingly dashed",
        "hopes of opening talks on a future trade deal with the EU looks increasingly likely to be dashed this autumn",
        "hopes to open talks on a future trade deal with the EU this autumn look likely to be increasingly dashed",
        "hopes of opening talks on a future trade deal this autumn with the EU look likely to be dashed increasingly",
        "hopes of opening talks on a future trade deal with the EU this autumn look increasingly likely to be dashed"
      ],
      "type": "Verbal Reasoning - Sentence Correction",
      "correct": 4,
      "explanations": [],
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    }
];